So, we're kind of out of a series in a series.
We have put together a series to walk through our vision and our mission and our core practices.
And Pastor Ryan was the gentleman who guided the team, that sought the Lord,
that began to articulate what it was we were facing, that God was calling us to,
and has practiced those items and has put it together in kind of a series.
And unfortunately, Ryan is not here.
So, rather than trying to prepare at his place, I mean, I want to hear what he has to say.
And I'm sure you want to hear what he has to say.
Last week, we came and did one of those messages out of order.
But I think you all got the concept, we're supposed to do 20 years.
And it's what we're called to.
It's how we're called by the Bible to live.
It's a key piece.
Rather than try to take one of those out of spec and perhaps someone else, when I was asked to preach today,
I'd like to share a message that I have been actually hoping to share in this room for over two years.
It's a message that is in my heart.
It's a message that I think the church needs to hear.
And as I discern the movement of God's spirit in our body,
I think it will resonate with who we are and how we behave as a body.
It's not listed in one of our core practices, but you tell me at the end if it resonates.
I think it's clearly biblical, but I think it's something that we do functionally, we behave in.
Full disclosure, it is a lecture that I'm turning into a sermon.
It's a lecture from my leadership class when I taught at the seminary.
I'll try to keep it more practical and less academic.
If I fail at that, you can let me know that, too.
But we'll try to.
Okay.
If you're having a chance to get that, mention that.
I know we have some technical difficulties today,
but that'll help me know whether it'll advance or not.
I suspect that most of you would hold the tone of servant leadership.
So, the kind of servant leadership was actually coined by Greenleaf back in an essay in 1970.
A lot of leadership thought, a lot of leadership principle has come out of Robert Greenleaf's essay.
And I think it's a very helpful term, because as I look at the life of Jesus,
I clearly see a servant leader.
I see one who came to serve, and in serving, actually lead these for us.
I had a colleague back in seminary who tried to develop an inventory on this whole servant leadership.
And I have to be honest, he didn't get it.
This is an inventory, but he did.
Servant is something here, and leadership is something here, and this continuum.
And the purpose of his inventory was to find out where you fell on this continuum of servant versus leader.
And that's missing the point.
It's kind of like saying, you know, is Jesus human or divine?
You know, where does he fall on the continuum?
Well, he falls 100% on the continuum as human and divine.
And so, too, the concept of servant leadership is that we are both fervent, and we are leaders.
Greenleaf made the comment in his essay, and it's part of what really made it take off,
that generally, high-quality leaders don't start with leadership.
They start with ferventhood.
The individuals who know the need to serve, feel the need to serve, and begin to serve in the midst of serving,
recognize this impetus, this falling, this bubbling up within them, this need to, in fact, lead.
What I find that really helpful is because it's actually what Paul describes of Jesus in Philippians chapter 2.
It's a passage that you're all familiar with.
But watch the flow of this passage, and notice in the flow of this passage that Paul is describing Jesus,
but in describing Jesus, he's saying, we are to be like Jesus.
So, this pattern that you see in Hebrews in Philippians 2, verses 5 through, I think it's like 11, something like that.
Yeah, 11.
It's something that he tells us that he tells us that we're to emulate.
Here it is.
I think I'm reading out of the NIV.
Yeah, NIV.
In our relationship with one another, have the same mindset as Christ Jesus.
Beginning in the very nature of God, did not consider equality with God something to be used for his own advantage.
But rather made himself nothing, or other translations say, emptied himself, by taking the very nature of a servant, and being made in human likeness, and being found in appearance as a man who humbled himself, and became obedient to death, even death on the cross.
So, Jesus, stepping into our existence here on earth, in his incarnation, and it says, from eternity into time, takes on the form of a servant.
Then Paul goes on to say, therefore, God exalted him to the highest place.
So, here is Jesus, who is fully God, in total union with the Father, in total union with the Spirit, in heaven, I don't know, in all life, in eternity, in everywhere, in everything, at all time, all at the same time.
And from that, he comes and steps into our time context.
And he says to the Spirit.
And the Scriptures tell us, because he did that, therefore, God exalted him to the highest place, and gave him a name that is above every name, that with the name of Jesus, every name shall be, in heaven, and on earth, and under the earth, and every tongue acknowledge that Jesus Christ is Lord, and not to the glory of the Father.
So, Jesus became the ultimate servant, and in becoming the ultimate servant, he became the ultimate leader.
And Paul says, would you kind of act like him a little bit?
Let's tell them.
I want to walk through that with you, if I can.
And so, in my 40 years of leading in the church, I kind of have done through probably about a dozen short-pissing statements that have formed a bedrock of my own leadership philosophy.
You've probably heard me mention some of them, you know, what you promote, so if you're going to leave, you've got to be careful about what you promote.
We preach what we know, what we reproduce, what we are.
People own what they help create.
I mean, there's about a dozen of them.
They just form a bedrock.
And this one in particular, that I want to talk about today, is one of those bedrock pieces for me that I think comes out of those root concepts, and then I'm going to focus on other concepts, the concepts you can't read today.
So, here's my premise.
Fervent leaders have responsibility.
Is that fair?
I mean, you've got to do something in your servant leadership.
Fervent leaders also have authority.
Because they have the, not just the responsibility to do it, but the capacity, the right, the authority to actually do it.
And then, a third one is privilege.
That along with authority, and along with responsibility, comes a privilege.
And it's my premise, that when those three are read well, that we do it the way Jesus did.
And I'm going to show you that in the Scriptures.
But much of what I want to talk about today, is when we don't do that well.
By the way, whenever I share this with people, they often go, no, wait a second, let's just privilege stuff.
Any of you get to fly on Air Force One?
I mean, why not?
You're as human as the president is, aren't you?
I mean, we're all important, aren't we?
We're all equally of value, aren't we?
Well, the truth is, I don't get to fly on Air Force One, because I don't have the same level of authority or responsibility that requires the privilege of having my own personal plane.
Now, when this church is 4,000, maybe we'll get one for me.
I don't know.
But at least at this point, there is a level.
We have people who have keys here, and people who don't.
That's a privilege.
Most of you probably are like, I don't want a key.
Not because you don't want the privilege, but you realize that there's an authority and responsibility that goes along with the privilege.
So, when we're writing three together, we find a whole functional servant leader.
And I would argue that whenever they get out of balance, we end up with a dysfunctional leader.
And let me see if I can show you that in the end of the passage that Kate read.
Let me get there if I'll go over with you as well.
Gospel of John.
Now, what's what Jesus is doing in this passage?
He is telling you that in some semblance, he's inviting you into a paradigm of leadership that parallels his.
He's inviting you into almost an earthly parity.
Now, that doesn't mean we're God.
I know some people want to think they're right.
But there's this invitation into this, as Jesus did, he now asks us to do.
Watch it as he goes through.
As the Father loved me, so I've loved you.
But is this between what I get or what you get?
If you keep my commandments, you will remain in my love just as I was.
You can open your Bibles if you want.
That's okay.
I mean, I love it when people check me.
That's pretty good.
As the Father has kept my commandments.
Oh, I'm sorry.
If you keep my commandments, you will remain in my love just as I have kept my Father's commandments and remain in his love.
I have told you this so that my joy may be in you and that your joy may be complete.
Again, it's what I receive and you receive.
It's what I get and what you get.
What I do and what you do.
My commandment is this.
Love each other.
How?
Thank you.
We're good.
People have to open the Bible.
That's good.
As I have loved you.
There's this, again, this invitation to us to be like Jesus.
I mean, isn't that really the Christian journey anyway?
All things work together for good for those who love God and are called according to his purpose.
For those who before knew, he could ask me what?
To be conformed into the image of his soul.
That there is this process of transformation that God is doing in you and in me and his followers.
And this process of transformation isn't just a personal benefit.
But God has a purpose for this transformation.
He has a plan for this transformation.
And as Jesus was a servant leader, Jesus is inviting us into the same kind of servant leadership paradigm.
By the way, I would argue that unless you are an infant on your deathbed, and even there, I don't know that there's an exemption,
or really sick, you are leading you something.
Now, the level of authority and responsibility and privilege must line up with whatever area you're leading in.
But what I really want to unpack today is this need, and I think, kind of a core practice for us that I think is core to who we are.
That we read this authority, if we ask you to do something, we give you authority to do it.
And there's usually some kind of privilege that enables you to actually do it.
Look at the graphic practice for you.
And you see the parallel between what Jesus did for you and his call to us, that in your leadership, you're to serve, in your service, you're to lead.
And he said, you're no longer, and he's going to say it in a little bit, I no longer just call you service, but I'm inviting you into a parity, into a model, into a way of moving in the kingdom of God that I have models for you and I want you to model to.
Greater love has no one in the midst that one lays down one's life for one's friends.
You are my friends if you do what I command.
And I no longer call you service, because a servant does not know his master's business.
Instead, I've called you friends.
For everything that I learned from my father, I've made known to you.
He's calling a thing to this paradigm.
You did not choose me, and here it is.
But I chose you and appointed you.
That in Jesus' calling of you, he's appointed you for something.
There is an inherent authority in his appointment.
Whether it is the authority of being a mother and raising your child, whether it's the authority of a pastor who's preaching the word of God, there is an authority that goes with that.
And it's something that he's inviting us into.
There's also a responsibility.
You did not choose me, but I chose you and appointed you so that you may bear fruit.
And fruit that will rise.
I don't know about you, but I'm really tired of bearing fruit that rise.
I want fruit that remains.
I really do.
Lord, help me.
Introduce me.
Teach me.
Lead me.
And I'm convinced that part of, and we'll see this later as I go through the message, that part of the reason the fruit remains is because we take a higher level of leadership than is servant leadership.
We don't just tell you what to do.
But we want to empower you to not just do it, but to go beyond it.
But servant leadership.
You did not choose me, but I chose you and appointed you so that you may go and bear fruit, fruit that will rise, so that whatever you ask in my name, I will give it to you.
Older, tell me.
I mean, could it come down bigger than that?
This is my command.
Love, woman, and the whole.
Okay, so for Ken, I want to now unpack this from kind of more dysfunctional perspectives.
See where we go wrong, because I think often when you go wrong, we can identify with where we need to correct in this whole process.
Okay, so have any of you ever met someone who just had more privilege and they had a quality or responsibility?
Do you know what I'm talking about here?
The thing we use for this is spoiled bread.
And some of us are actively raising one.
And we have to be rewarded, careful.
By the way, Proverbs says it this way: "An inheritance obtained early in life is not a blessing in the end."
You know, my parents were very financially responsible.
Thank you, mom.
She's probably watching.
Thank you.
And we've talked about leaving us an inheritance.
But I remember early on saying to my parents, "Look, you, you, everything that you owed me, you gave me.
You loved me and raised me responsibly.
You don't owe me anything else."
And you've done an amazing job.
I mean, so you can do just about anything you want with what you have, what you've gained over your life.
But I do remember at one point, and, because you know, I've seen personal kids sometimes have tension.
Is that true?
Is it as a sign or as a dad?
That's the question.
You don't have to answer.
That's okay.
It's both, yeah.
So I remember at one point, saying to my parents, because I think they exploded something, I said, "You know, you can do anything you want.
If you want to travel the world, you want to spend it, you want to give it away, I mean, it's yours.
If you want to give it to me, that's okay, too.
You know, that's acceptable."
The only thing that if you do this, I'm going to fight you, is if you bypass Lori and me and give it to the rest of my kids, particularly when they're young.
And at this point, they're getting you a place where I might trust them.
They're responsible, they're good, but, you know, if I had gotten inheritance early on, I wouldn't be here today.
It wouldn't be good.
Proverbs warns us about this.
If we have too much privilege, without a commensurate authority and responsibility.
By the way, another adult term for this is narcissism.
Jack Wells, Robert Quinn, business leaders, both said that the hardest leadership job is dealing with high performers
who won't live by the organizations that are in their enemies.
If you've ever worked in an office where there's just a really high performer, the rainmaker,
who treats everyone like the bottom of the bone.
And both of them said that, well, that's one of the hardest leadership decisions.
You must deal with it.
Because if you don't, it will destroy the morale and the whole organization.
When people are allowed to live cleanly, without the appropriate authority and responsibility,
it actually begins to erode the organization from within.
Robert Quinn tells the story of one particular company that he was working with.
And they had this, they had a rainmaker.
He was amazing, he knew he was a rainmaker, and he made sure everyone else knew he was a rainmaker.
He wouldn't do what the boss would tell him to do.
He would tell the boss what to do.
He didn't follow the rules.
He was exempt from all of them.
And Quinn said to the CEO, you have to let that crowd go.
You've tried to correct the behavior, you refuse to be corrected, and you have to let him go.
And so eventually the gentleman went to him and said, mess up your box, you're done today.
But he couldn't believe it, through a bit, everyone in the office knew it was a problem because he let everyone know.
You know, I'm the soul of this organization, you're going to destroy, you're going to fall asleep.
And Quinn said that he's actually there, because the boss asked him to be there for moral support.
And he said, this guy got up the box, walked out of his office, he walked down the hallway, and people started coming to the door.
And just kind of looking as he's walking down, he just kind of ground all of them, and goes out the door, pushes it, the door closes.
No more does the door close.
And a lady stands out, and she quotes the good witch of the north.
When the hills spun and fell on the wicked witch of the east.
And she said, let the glorious news spread, the wicked old witch is at last bed.
And he said, everyone came out of their offices and marched up and down.
Ding dong, the witch is there, the wicked, witch is there.
She's willing to say that the company, actually, they took a hit.
But within six months, their numbers were exceeding the numbers that they were six months prior.
And not only that, they had a retention problem, and the retention problem didn't happen.
There's something about morale that we're not greater than.
We're fervent.
Anyway, ferventhood, we need.
And sometimes that leadership, it gives us some dignity.
It's privilege.
And it's okay.
But we don't take it for you.
You get it.
Okay.
I'll move through the rest of these a little quicker.
So, this is the one that the other one loves.
The narcissist loves the person who will do whatever they tell him to do.
And actually, it's a nice pro-dependent relationship for one.
It actually works really well because the person who has all this responsibility with very little privilege, very little authority, they get their identity from this superhero, this performer.
And it works really well until it doesn't.
And that's the problem.
That we see it working, and then when it doesn't, it tends to go fast really bad.
The word for this is slave.
And it may be slave in your business that may be...
Do you ever work for a boss like this?
You know, Christian and me today did a podcast.
A whole series of podcasts on what went wrong with Martyrs Hill.
And I listened to them.
Some of them were good.
Some were okay.
But the one that I really appreciated was Tim Tellers.
They interviewed him because he had this unbelievable success.
And he talked about his own journey from this unbelievable success of having to...
Early on, he just made decisions and just did what he wanted to do.
And at some point, he realized that if he continued to do that, it would actually hurt the organization.
And so he began to give over authority, began to give over...
He actually began to reproduce himself in others.
You see, that's the problem with someone who takes all their privilege.
They need to prove them that they don't want to make you a better you.
That's the problem with this person.
They're doing all this stuff, but no one's trying to make them a better them.
They're just trying to...
Heaturing and machinery in the organization.
They're just trying to get something from them.
This is kind of a spunk in the works of theology that some of us can fall into.
We keep saying something, folks.
You know, the codependent and Christians can sometimes look the same.
Different motivations.
I mean, that's a whole other message.
We don't care about it too much.
Okay.
So here's another one.
Loss of authority.
Very much less responsibility.
Much less privilege.
This we call a micromanager.
Highly productive micromanagers will expel until they breed too many concubent leaders.
By the way, that's true in the church too.
There are churches that can grow exponentially early on because they have a high-performing micromanager.
And they get stuff done.
And it works until too many other competent, solid, good, healthy leaders say, "I can't work under this anymore."
And when the organization breeds too many of those, it becomes problematic.
Only once in my life I've ever worked for someone like that.
I've got to tell you, it didn't end well.
I'm pretty good at setting boundaries, particularly around controlling personalities.
But if someone is seeing this as kind of their call for leadership, they're doing good stuff except when it comes to doing good stuff in me.
They'll do good stuff through me.
Maxwell did this wonderful thing about leadership, five levels of leadership.
He said, you know, the first level of leadership is your role.
People will follow you because you're the boss.
People will do what you say because you're the boss.
Now, you only do so much for the boss.
But at some point, you need to move beyond your role of leadership from, you don't just do it because I'm the boss.
But I get you to do it because of my relationship.
That we actually have a meaningful relationship.
You trust me.
I honor you.
I trust you.
You trust me.
And now you want to be productive, not just because of my role, but because of our relationship.
And then Maxwell says, at some point, you get to the place of results.
You want to be part of an organization that actually makes a difference.
When we hear the reports of the mission trip in Tennessee with blazing hope, and we hear what's happening and hear the testimonies, it's wonderful.
Yesterday, Mike talked about the number of men who are now going over to the kids' club and reading to the kids.
Not just women, but we're getting men doing it as well.
And how cool that is because most of these kids have no solid male role model in their life.
There's someone who pours into them.
So, results are good.
But here's the place where Jesus wants to take us.
And it's what he's doing in that passage I read just a little bit ago in John 15.
It's not just about my, you do it because I'm your boss, my role.
It's not just because of our relationship.
It's not just because it works, you get results.
You have to reproduce.
That life makes you a better you.
I often think that this congregation is working at doing that way.
I watch, one quick example.
Donovan does a great job leading.
I'd be thrilled if we just stood up here and led every single time I'm with his capacity and ability.
And yet, if you watch how often someone else is up here leading.
Someone else is taking this time.
Maybe he's leading, but someone else is leading this time.
Because the goal is not just to produce great worship for you.
That's a goal.
That's a result that we want.
But the goal goes far beyond that.
The goal is discipleship.
And it's not just discipleship of you who are receiving, but of the people who are giving.
It's discipleship of the bass player and the keyboardist and the vocalist and the drummer and everyone on the team.
It's about reproducing yourself.
It's what Jesus was all about with his walls, folks.
He said, I only got three years.
He sent them out.
They messed it up.
They came back and he taught them.
And then he sent them out again.
And they did well.
But they came back and they were rejoicing over the wrong things.
And Jesus corrected them again.
Because Jesus was about reproducing himself in others.
This person has no plan for them.
Jesus said, all authority is given unto me.
Hasn't he right?
In those very next words, we're basically unpacking.
And take that aside and then go do it.
Teach.
Make disciples.
Be disciples.
Do the things that...
By the way, I love that you have multiple people doing baptizing.
To me, that's as much the discipleship as the actual baptizing that they're doing.
I'm thrilled with them.
Speaking of which, I just got a request this morning.
Well, we're going to throw up the tub on Sunday.
And we're going to do another baptism.
And yes, woo-hoo!
And so, if any of you have not yet followed the Lord in water baptism,
the water will be here.
Just for us, you let us know ahead of time.
But we'll have to tell us here whether you let us know ahead of time or not.
If you would like to follow the Lord in water baptism, I'll give you a great opportunity to do that.
Okay.
That's not part of my message.
Sorry.
This is a place where people that want to self-absorb leave some positions.
It's part of my message.
Okay.
Here's a case where people have too much responsibility but very little authority.
And I want to say at this point that this is not necessarily an inappropriate form of leadership.
It's a contextual form of leadership.
We call this a sonny.
Or an acquaintance.
I have a parenting kind of principle that we try to follow with our kids and I recommend it to other parents.
When your kid is 2, they should make 2 out of 20 decisions.
When they're 14, they should be making 14 out of 20 decisions.
Because your goal is to actually raise the kids in a way where they love you, but they're independent from you.
Really important, I think.
Yeah, we've got one amen.
That's good.
I actually was in a car with my first pastor.
It was an evangelical car.
And two teenagers were sitting back there with me and mom was taking the M&M bag and she was dividing the M&Ms to give them to her kids.
Really?
You know what?
They're 18 and 50?
And she's not just dividing the M&Ms so they get equal numbers of M&Ms.
Yes!
She was separating out the killers.
So they all got the same number of girls.
Actually better than me, I got like three.
And she was just dividing the M&Ms.
And she was dividing the M&Ms to give them to her kids.
And she was dividing the M&Ms so they get equal numbers of M&Ms.
Yes!
She was separating out the killers.
So they all got the same number of girls.
Actually better than me, I got like three blue and a green, you know?
And I'm like, what are you doing?
And she was dividing the M&Ms to give them to her kids.
And she's not just dividing the M&Ms so they get equal numbers of M&Ms.
Yes!
She was separating out the killers.
So they all got the same number of girls.
Actually better than me, I got like three blue and a green, you know?
And I'm like, what are you doing?
Well, we have to be saved.
Yeah.
Well, you can say more about that.
You get the common sense.
By the way, an apprenticeship.
If you're apprenticing someone, if you're pouring yourself into someone else, here's a place
where you don't give them the game.
If you don't give them the good.
Okay.
Um.
By the way.
Here's Paul's instructions around this.
In 2 Timothy 2.
And the things that you have heard.
Me say.
In the presence of many.
Entrust to reliable people.
Who will also be qualified to teach others.
This is a level of 4.
Timothy.
It would be seemingly.
Give over to others.
Who can give it to others.
This is the reproduction model.
That's the place of giving away authority.
But notice in the same.
Well.
To the same person.
Different letter.
But the same person.
He also says.
They do not be too hasty in the laying on of hands.
So.
Don't.
Be careful in the giving of this authority.
That they're responsible with it.
This is the idea of apprenticeship.
So the goal is.
To give away the authority.
And to do it in the appropriate sense.
Okay.
I think you get that.
I think it's one of the worst things.
Maybe not.
It's close.
So.
Here's a place where.
I have very little responsibility.
I have lots of authority.
Lots of privilege.
This is.
This is a guest spot.
This is a playboy.
I gave two examples up there on the screen.
But let me give you a biblical example.
Jesus poses a fireman.
He talks about the difference between a good shepherd.
And a fireman.
this is a playboy
I gave two examples up there on the screen
but let me give you a biblical example
Jesus poses the fireling
he talks about the difference
between a good shepherd
and a fireling
and the fireling
has authority and privilege
that when the wolf comes
just abandons the responsibility
it's a good shepherd
that's not the way the good shepherd plays it
we used to say
I was a long distance runner
we used to say when the going gets tough
the sprinters get out
this is kind of a sprinter mode
and God is calling us
for fruit that remains
that's his goal
in developing us as disciples
of Jesus Christ
and so the goal here
is that we read
the authority and the privilege
and the responsibility
and I think you get that
whereas Jesus
who is the good shepherd
he lays down his life for the sheep
but remember the shepherd owns the sheep
and I think it's really important
for us in the kingdom
because God
God does so much for us
he's much about us
he loves us
he forgives us
he equips us
he empowers us
he gives marvelous comrades
to many of the faithful
who dwell on the land
obviously he heals
I mean there is so much
that God does
where I am the receiver
and that is
it is not only legitimate
it's right
but in and of itself
it is sufficient
because we must always remember
that the sheep
exists
ultimately
for the purposes
of the shepherd
ultimately
we're here for God
and one of the references
to confession
is the purpose of man
is to glorify God
for God
and enjoy Him
and see John Piper says
to enjoy Him
by His glory for Him
that we're supposed to enjoy
but we enjoy the glory
from God
that there is this reality
that we
belong to Him
and while He does so much
for us
His purpose
is to use us
in His kingdom
and this reason
is my last one
and it's the place
where
pastors often
get it run
where authority
and responsibility
outweigh
privilege
notice I put
Christian readers
in Corinthians
I think there are
long time
before I know
that
burnout
is not a function
of doing too much
it's not
if it is
then
we're going to be
in potential burnout
if we follow Jesus
because Jesus
calls us to give it all
we're called
to give it all
but that's not
what it means
to burnout
burnout
is not a function
of giving too much
burnout
as a function
of trying
to give
what you have
not received
I've watched
Jesus
for the last
two decades
I've heard
in roles
where we watched
pastors
who desperately
needed to receive
fresh
from God
in order
to give
I have a moment
of a period
of time
in my own life
where
for the sake
of the kingdom
of the gospel
I couldn't
find time
to allow
God
to fill me
and so I was
sending my bucket
down my well
and all that was there
was the muck
at the bottom
of the well
and scooping it up
bringing it up
working the water
getting it
pouring water
and then being
frustrated
because the
mucky water
I'm giving
to someone
they don't want
Parker Palmer
said this
quote
by surviving
procedures
of doubt
and depression
on the vocational
journey
I would become
clear
about at least
one thing
self-care
is never
a selfish act
it's simply
good stewardship
of the only
thing
I truly
have to do
it's why
I had to
learn
fresh
the concept
of status
of going
out
and coming
in
a rhythm
and for pastors
that's often
hard because
you know
for many people
they said
it's today
well let me tell you
this ain't no
status for me
folks
this is three
days of work
but that doesn't
exempt me
from needing
that rhythm
of going out
and coming in
and you do
realize that
one of the
things the
church
it's a thing
the church
will reward
it's
performance
addiction
and that's
not just
true of
pastors
it's true
of all
kinds of
ministry leaders
that we
love people
who give
and they
give of
themselves
and we
preach that
you can
give
and we
want to be
a church
that calls
you
not just
to be
a peace
litter
because that's
not discipleship
because there
has to be
this rhythm
of going
out
Jesus said
my seat
hear my voice
they come in
and they go
out
I'm the
door
spirit
and sign
up in
as they
go
out
and they
come in
there is
this
privilege
of
fast
care
of
parking
time
of
meeting
with
Jesus
of being
renewed
John
Gideau
said
only the
mediocre
are always
at their
base
you know
Jesus
willingly
went to
the
cross
but you
will not
find in
the Bible
Jesus
speaking
his
cross
the early
church
the first
300 years
of the
church
there were
a lot
of martyrs
there were
martyrs
who died
there were
the people
they called
the living
martyrs
but the
early church
was very
clear about
martyrdom
that it was
a gift
and it was
never to
be found
there were
two young
people who
would go
out for
their own
ego
purposes
I want
a legacy
a name
and would
literally
seek
martyrdom
and sometimes
I hear
the message
we give
to people
in the
church
today
why does
not
call us
to seek
martyrdom
it is not
better to
burn out
than it
is to
rest
it's better
to do
even
it's better
to go
out
and to
come in
to go
out
and to
come in
to give
it all
for Jesus
but only try
to give
it to
receive
it takes
that time
to receive
from him
so when
you take
your
bucket
down
there's
just a
pile of
water
down
it's
good
and
refreshing
clean
there is
a few
of
not just
pastors
to
parents
not just
parents but
ministry leaders
small group
leaders
now I
suspect there
are some
of you who
probably need
your butt
kicked and
you need
to go do
something
for Jesus
but there's
probably
a lot of
you here
who need
to hear
rest
receive
that you
might get
and I'll
let the
Holy Spirit
be the one
to tell you
which you
are
because the
reality of
this full
breath
saying much
is given
more is
desired
you ever
need a
full breath
to say
if you're a
martyr
because the
spirit
can't keep
the garbage
out
we have
to be careful
we're not
there
but rather
be careful
that with our
responsibility
and our
authority
that's
appropriately
given to
us
that we
make sure
also have
the privilege
that comes
along with it
I'm going to
end with one
more slide
so if our
band can make
their way up
to lead us
in a closing
song
so folks
whether
your
service
is
cutting
pasties
or leading
a mission
trip
if we
as a
court
are
failing
to
encourage
you
in
appropriate
authority
and
responsibility
privilege
come talk
to us
we
require
our
board
members
to have
a portfolio
outside of
just the
board
they need to
have an
authority
and a
responsibility
or an
area
of the
church
because
one of the
worst things
I've ever
seen
is a church
where all
the board
members
do
is make
decisions
and have
no
responsibilities
outside of
making decisions
all they
want to do
is tell you
what to
do
and then
go do
their own
thing
and so
we try
to say
how can
we
read
authority
and
responsibility
and privilege
all
together
how can
we keep
this
in a
balanced
way
so that
people
are actually
being
discipled
to be
like
Jesus
now
if
you
are
sick
if
you've
been
wounded
injuries
that
aren't
rehabbed
they
become
disabilities
and so
if
you're
here
and
you
are
feeling
some
kind
of
spiritual
abuse
some
kind
of
church
dysfunction
some
kind
of
bad
theology
like
mine
where
I
thought
you
know
that
redeeming
requirements
lifting
more and
more
things
into
the
same
hour
which
doesn't
mean
then
come
and
heal
receive
but at
some
point
you've
got to
reheat
because
if
you
don't
get
those
muscles
working
again
if
you
just
come
and
just
listen
and
receive
go
home
and
do
your
things
you
will
not
be
a
heart
secret
moment
we need
to
read
this
authority
and
responsibility
Jesus
said
excuse
me
I
have
point
you
he's
giving
you
authority
now
we saw
the
authority
goes
and
there's
fruit
that
remains
there's
fruit
that
was
and
while
you're
doing
it
whatever
you
ask
let's
be a
church
that
leads
and
supports
our
leaders
in a
healthy
way
would you
stand
before
the
Lord
as many
as we
stand
in a
closing
hand
We'll see you next time.